can you tell me, when do you remember the
можешь мне сказать Э когда ты помнишь
last time you had a rally or strike in Russia, for example,
последний раз у вас в России например
a meeting or a strike
митинг или забастовку
of Trade Unions, a meeting or a reserve of
Профсоюзов митинг или запасовка
Trade Unions? Well, with trade unions. By the way,
Профсоюзов Ну с профсоюзами Да кстати
you can say that it’s not very good in Russia.
вот можно сказать не очень в России А
Why is this exactly one of the foundations of
почему это же как раз одна из осново
socialism? Communism is a strong labor
социализма Коммунизм это сильные рабочее
movement Yes  trade unions that protect the
движения Да профсоюзы которые защищают
rights of workers
права рабочих
Hello Hello You are 18 years old
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вам 18 лет
of course I understand the special operation
есть конечно име Понял спецоперацию
you support the special operation itself yes
поддерживаете саму спецоперацию да А
Can you explain
можете объяснить
why first  this is the choice of my
почему вопервых это выбор моего
government WOH In general, based on
правительства ВОХ В общем по
ideological
идеологическим
interests, you support it under the influence of
интересам поддерживаете под действие
your government. And what does the
своего правительства А причём
Constitution have to do with it? And what does it have to do with you being a citizen of the
Конституция А причём что вы гражданин
Russian
Российской
Federation? Well, I’m just a citizen of the
Федерации Ну просто я гражданин
Russian Federation. I live on this
Российской Федерации Я живу на этой
land. And these are my fellow citizens. Where is it
земле И это мои сограждане Да где
written down about citizenship? where is it written down in
записано про гражданство где записано в
which
каком
document?  What exactly is written down, what is the
документе Что именно записа нство что
Russian Federation? Yes, not that you
Российской Федерации Да не что у вас
have citizenship, the rights and duties of a
есть гражданство права и обязанности
citizen, where it is written in the Constitution, in the
гражданина где записано в Конституции в
Constitution, there
Конституции вот абсолю
is an absolute duty in the Constitution
ва есть в Конституции обязанность
to support  your
поддерживать сво
government No, this is not an obligation. You
правительство Нет это не обязательство
see. That is, you have no
вот Вот видите То есть у вас нет
obligation to support your
обязанности поддержать своё
government. Why do you
правительство то Почему вы его
support it in this
поддерживаете в этом
matter? I will explain it to you again because
деле я вам ещ раз это объясню потому что
I am a citizen of this country and because these are
я гражданин этой страны и потому что это
my fellow citizens, these are the actions of my
мои сограждане это действи моего
state.
государства
Well, exactly.  not everything is clear, but well, that
Ну именно не все понятное дело а ну так
means you will support not because
значит вы поддержите не из-за того что
you are a citizen but because of some other
вы гражданин а из-за каких-то других
motives Well, because these are my fellow
побуждений Ну потому что это мои также
citizens, you already have a full
сограждане уже вам полный
complex of howls, wait, that is,
комплекс выли подожди То есть получается
everything that they do turns out  your fellow citizens You should
Всё что делают ваши сограждане Вы должны
support So, well, this is what I
поддерживать Так ну это действи
support. Wait, you will support it
поддерживаю Подождите вы поддержите изза
because it’s there for you, your fellow citizens,
того что оно вам там ваши сограждане
but how well it rocks. By the way, it’s very
но как хорошо раскачивает Кстати очень
interesting, yes, yes, very interesting in
интересно да да да очень интересно в
terms of
плане
this. It’s
этого
just that you somehow
Просто вы очень как-то
know very deeply about this, yes I I
знаете прям углублённо в этого да я я в
I’ll hit you right at the root Yes, because in this
корень прямо бью Да потому что в таком
case, if you can tell Dasha,
случае если вы можете Даше сказать Типа
like, well, let’s say who else from the
вот а вот допустим че другого со
citizen of the Russian Federation, who should I
гражданина Российской Федерации кого
support? That’s
поддерживать
right, you’re great, you’re a very
я больше правильно ты молодец ты очень
good student  quickly Look, now I’ll
хорошо учишься быстро Смотри Я теперь
ask you if tomorrow your country
тебя спрошу если завтра ваша страна
announces, for example, let us all citizens of
объявит например давайте мы всех граждан
Estonia. So you will support this
Эстонии Так ты будешь это поддерживать
because it’s your citizens who
потому что это твои граждане
are doing this; you won’t really, I don’t know, I can’t
делают не будешь правда не знаю не могу
say. Well, that is, you’re already
сказать Ну то есть ты как бы уже
starting to think that it’s not Damn I’m
начинаешь задумываться что не Блин я
done  -I support it not because
всё-таки поддерживаю не изза того что
it’s a game, but because of something else. Well, this is
это игра а из-за чего-то другого Ну это
one of the not. No, that is, it’s not, it’s not
одно из не Не ну то есть это не это не
decisive, well, uh, well, why? Well, this is
есть решающее ну как бы э Ну почему Ну
completely my opinion; what I
это полностью моё мнение того что я
support is consistent with-  there are no factors for these
поддерживаю сходится из-за этих факторов
Well, look, that is, we understand that
нет Ну смотри то есть мы поняли да что
you support it. Not because your
ты поддерживаешь Не потому что там твои
citizens are there. Yes, because you
граждане Да потому что
see, in another case, if it were
видишь в другом случае если бы это были
your citizens, you wouldn’t care. Yes, you
твои граждане тебе бы пофиг было Да ты
told me this is [ __ ], that is, so
сказал мнени это фигня то есть Так
explain why you support it if
объясни почему ты поддерживаешь вот если
we take out the citizens  out of brackets,
вынесем граждан за скобки
you just have the opinion that you understand each
у вас просто мнение в том что Вы каждый
individual fact
отдельный факт
into the Absolute as if it were the
разбираетесь его в Абсолют как будто он
only one in this essence, but I
единственный в этом суть но я вам ещё
tell you again that I gave you three Well,
раз говорю что я вам назвал целых три Ну
three reasons are approximately
три причины примерно
A and each is in  something piece by piece
А и каждый является в чём-то по кусочку
makes up the overall picture of my support
составляет общую картину моей поддержки
Which three do you say that you are a
Какие три ты скажешь что это ты
citizen of this country and the second that you
гражданин этой страны и второе что ты
ideologically support it two that
идеологически это поддерживаешь две что
these are my fellow citizens Well, well this
это мои сограждане Ну так это ж это ж с
coincides with the first that you are a citizen of this
первым совпадает что ты гражданин этой
country, that is, your fellow citizens  they kill
страны то есть твои сограждане убивают
you of the same citizenship, this is one
ты с ними одного гражданства это один
argument, and the second argument is that you
аргумент а второй аргумент - это что ты
ideologically support it. Yes, with the
идеологически это поддерживаешь Да с
first argument, we realized that this is
первым аргументом мы поняли что это
an excuse. Yes, in other cases you would not
отмазка Да что в других случаях ты бы не
support me; they thought now. And
поддерживал отменя подумали тепер А
now  tell me your ideological ones
теперь расскажи свои идеологические
What is your ideology What is the name of
Какая у тебя идеология Как называется
your ideology Well, in general I have a
твоя идеология Ну у меня вообще
Communist ideologue And you are a
Коммунистическая идеологи А ты ты
communist Yes wow I’m just wearing the wrong T-
коммунист Да вау я просто не в той
shirt not super super That is, is this a
футболке не супер супер То есть
real communist or just like
это реальный коммунист или просто Типа
that, you’re showing off
так понтуешься
your butt, well, really That is, I can’t
попой ну реально То есть я не могу
boast of enormous knowledge in
похвастаться огромными знаниями в
literature understood understood then you are a
литературе понял понял то ты
communist in some way yes yes understood Your
коммунист в чём-то да да понял Твоя
country is Russia it is Socialist
страна Россия она Социалистическая
Communist or capitalist
Коммунистическая или капиталистическая
capitalist capitalist That
капиталистическая капиталистическая То
is, you are like a communist  you support the
есть ты как коммунист поддерживаешь
capitalist now Well, well done you
капиталистическая Ну молодец ты это
said that Explain why you are a communist
сказал Объясни почему ты коммунист
who is a Communist he must think about
который Коммунист он должен мыслить
international
интернациональное
expansion the imperialist war
экспансию империалистическую войну
correctly well done imperialist
правильно молодец империалистическая
The point is that the Empire is grossly
Суть в том что Империя грубо
imperialist, in communism it is
империалистическая она в коммунизме в
generally interpreted very strangely but it
основном трактуется очень странно но
is possible If we say so to
можно Если уж так сказать
the capitalist that it is simply impe  a
капиталистическому что импе она просто
world war starts then it is already a
исходит мировой войне тогда уже
capitalist war because on the
капиталистической войну потому что и с
other side there is capital
той стороны с той стороны есть капитал
that is lobbying for its  interests in the war
который лоббирует свои интересы во война
in your head now in Ukraine there are
в твоей голове сейчас в Украине бьётся
two imperialisms fighting Yes, Russian and
два империализма Да российский и
American imperialism
американский империализм
Well, that’s if It depends on how exactly you
Так ну это если Смотря как именно
look at capital Well, capital is
смотреть так капитал Ну так капитал
Ukrainian and Russian And if
украинский и российский А если
imperialism is most likely
империализм то скорее всего да
American and look, it’s not
американский и смотри не это ж
imperialism, not separate from  capital goes
империализм не отрыв от капитала идёт
there if you read all this correctly, yes,
там если ты правильно это всё читал да
that is, well, look at
то есть ну смотрите
imperialism Yes, and capital enters into imperialism
а империализм Да и в империализм входит
But
капитал Но
there are still these very  the
именно есть же всё-таки вот эти самые
imperialist habits that people like to
империалистические замашки которые любят
talk about are basically people like this.
говорить в основном такие вот люди Вот
Look, if I take Marx’s this
смотри если я возьму вот марксовское эту
Yes Lenin What Say, imperialism is
Да Ленин Что Говори вот империализм есть
capitalism at that stage of development when the
капитализм на той стадии развития когда
dominance of the monopoly of
сложилось господство монополии
financial capital has acquired And so
финансового капитала приобрёл И так
on, and so on, that is, imperialism - This is a
дальше да то есть империализм - Это
form of capitalism according to Lenin  if you are a
форма капитализма по Ленину если ты
communist, then look, it turns out that
коммунист да то смотри получается что
now
сейчас
two imperialisms, Russian and
Украине два империализма российский и
American, are fighting in your head, fighting in Ukraine. Yes  their capital then why are
американский Да ихний капитал то почему
you? Well, it’s not capital. Most likely,
ты Ну тут не капитал Скорее всего
imperialist habits in terms of
империалистические замашки в плане
ownership and division of the world. Well, look.
владения и разделения мира Ну смотри
Why are you a communist who should be
Почему ты коммунист который должен быть
for the world International, I understand correctly
за мировой Интернационал я правильно
under Yes, I’m most likely equality,
поде Да ну меня скорее всего равенство
yes, why are you who should stand
да да почему ты который должен выступать
for the world proletariat  Yes, for the dictatorship
за мировой пролетариат Да за диктатуру
of the proletariat for uh domination This is the
пролетариата за ээ господство Вот это
Working Class Yes why do you
Рабочего класса Да почему ты
support uh one imperialist
поддерживаешь ээ одну империалистическую
capitalist well because one of the
капиталистического ну потому что одна из
capitalist powers  uh, it’s all the same to
капиталистических держав э всё равно ВК
one degree or another Although this is one of the
той или мере Хотя это является одной из
beginnings of a special operation, this is denazification
начало спецоперации это денацификация
itself and the Armed Forces are equally present in one of these
самое и ВС равно в одной из вот этих
capitalist countries, to
капиталистических стран присутствует в
one degree or another, the emergence of nationalism,
той или иной мере появление национализма
wait again Look, you live in the
подожди ещё раз Смотри ты живёшь в
Russian Federation, yes you have
Российской Федерации да у вас есть
nationalism
национализм
there  nationalism is prohibited but like in
там национализм запрещён но как и в
any country it
любой стране он
exists, this is already an
есть это уже
exaggeration in one country
утрирование в одной стране
doesn’t mean s I understood understood understood Look That
не значи с я понял понял понял Смотри То
is, what do you think in ROSI in Russian
есть как ты думаешь в РОСИ в Российской
Federations Yes,
Федерации Да
now there is nationalism at the
сейчас есть национализм на
state level, no, so if you
государственном уровне нет так если вы
give me 12 theses of an Italian
мне приведёте 12 тезисов итальянского
writer Why do I need writers? No, why do
писателя Зачем мне писатели Нет зачем
I need some kind of writers like you, some kind of
мне писатели какие-то что ты каких-то
writers? I see, I’m asking, that is,
писателей Я вот смотрю спрашиваю то есть
in Russia now there is internationalism
в России сейчас интернационализм
and the state if the level if
да государством если уровне если
you look  to the Constitution then yes Super yes
заглянуть в Конституцию то да Супер да
What language do children study in schools in
На каком языке учатся дети в школах
Udmurtia in Udmurtia in their native language but in the
Удмуртии в Удмуртии на родном но в
Republic this is allowed What native language
Республике это разрешено На каком родном
do they study in? Show me at least  one school Where in
учатся Покажи мне хоть одну школу Где в
Udmurtia they teach children in the Udmurt language
Удмуртии на удмуртском языке обучают
I need data now, but
детей Мне нужно сейчас данные при нету
there are no such schools, no, look at some, I’m
таких школ есть нет смотри в некоторых
sure yes, I’m asking from Udmurt,
уверен точно да я и с удмурта спрашиваю
more precisely, there isn’t a single one. There are schools where the
точне ни одной нету Есть школы в которых
Udmurt language is studied twice a week.
изучается два раза в неделю удмуртский
Do you know how to study English?
язык знаешь как английский изучаешь два
twice a week and Udmurt and everything
раза в неделю так и удмуртский а всё
else is in Russian Yes
остальное на русском идёт Да
in Tatarstan let’s say in Chechnya in
в в Татарстане допустим в Чечне в
Dagestan in Chechnya yes  tell me Show me a
Дагестане в Чечне да скажи Покажи мне
textbook in the Chechen language a
учебник на чеченском языке учебник
mathematics textbook Show me it’s really possible on the
математики Покажи реально можно в
Internet now it’s interesting let’s
интернете сейчас интересно давай
eat it
вот есть
So for the thirty-second year
Так за тридцать второй год
there is based on Latin graphics and the
есть на основе Латинской графики ри
second is what year it was under
второй - это какой год ещё при
Stalin There is no more new new
Сталине Нет более новы новй
fashion Mot
мод Моть
[music]
[музыка]
is taught in Chechnya  all the subjects are in
в Чечне преподают все предметы на
Chechen I can’t, I need to look at this,
чеченском не могу это же нужно смотреть
well, look, you’re giving me some
вот ну посмотри вы даёте какие-то мне
data that’s just so accurate,
данные которые прямо вот такие точные
which Well, well, I’m not, I just thought that you were
которые Ну ну я не я просто думал что ты
like that  true communist You
такой вот истинный коммунист Ты про свою
know well about your country, but I don’t know, I do
страну хорошо знаешь я же не знаю я же
n’t live in your country.
не в твоей стране
It’s the same if you
живу Это то же самое если вы мне
ask me the question How many diamonds
зададите вопрос Сколько алмазов
are there or how many pechinos are there
находится или сколько печино находится
on the Sakhalin beach? I understand But look,
на сахалинском пляже понял А вот смотри
this can also be attributed, let’s do it,
это тоже можно приписать давайте так
let me  I understand, let's go here
давайте я понял давайте мы зайдём вот
Izhevsk Udmurtia Yes, let's go to the website of the
Ижевск Удмуртия Да зайдём на сайт
Izhevsk city council in what
городского совета Ижевска на каком он
language is it in Udmurt and Russian or in
языке на удмуртском и русском или на
Russian only in Russian because
русском только на русском потому что
Russian is the state language
русский является государственным языком
Oh, that’s why in national
О вот а почему в национальных
republics Yes,
республиках Да
uh, the Imperial language is used and not the
ээ Имперский язык используется а не
local languages ​​of local
местные языки местных
Nations, well, well, because, firstly, there is
Наций м ну ну потому что во-первых есть
the concept of a state law
понятие государственный зака
enshrined in the Constitution. And
закреплённого Конституции А почему
why why and why did your state
почему а почему ваше государство
enshrine it for
закрепило для
all these peoples, yes not  enslaved And
всех этих народов да не порабощенный А
free Yes, the language of the titular
свободных Да язык титульной
nation Well, because
нации Ну потому
of the Constitution and for a greater understanding of
что Конституции и для большего понимания
people, because more
людей потому что большее количество
people understand
людей понимает именно
the pack of communists. So you
свору коммунист Так ты за международный
would be for the international International, so yeah, well, but here it
Интернационал был бы так угу ну а тут
turns out that  imperialist Moscow
получается что империалистическая Москва
Yes, it imposes its culture
Да навязывает народом тем свою культуру
and its
и свой
language on the people. Well, of course, it imposes it because
язык Ну как поняти навязывает потому что
it is a national language.
он является общегосударственным языком
So why is it
Так почему он является
a national language so that everyone
общегосударственным для того чтобы все
understands? No, why does it impose it? It’s
понимали Нет почему его навязывает
clear because so that every
Понятное дело потому что чтобы каждый
person, let’s say, even in Chechnya, even in
человек Допустим хоть в Чечне хоть на
Chukotka, understands  let’s say I
Чукотке понимал друг друга вот допустим
don’t understand each other Yes, but why are people being
о не понимаю Да но почему у людей
deprived of the right to study in their
забирают право учиться на своём
Udmurt language? Yes, in the Chechen language,
удмуртском языке Да на чеченском языке
in Buryat why? Well, show me  show
на бурятском почему Ну покажи мне покажи
me schools in the Buryat language that. That
мне школы на бурятском языке которые То
is, I need to find the data directly for you.
есть мне нужно прямо вам данные найти
Yes, I wonder how many schools there are in
что Да вот интересно сколько есть в
Buryatia that do full
бурятий школ которые делают полностью
education in the Buryat language, not just
обучение на бурятском языке не просто
study the Buryat language twice a week.
изучают бурятский язык два раза в неделю
I’m interested,
Вот мне интересно
I see news for 20  last year
вот я вижу новость за 20 за прошлый год
that in the schools of Buryatia, from September 1, they will begin
что в школах Бурятии с 1 сентября начнут
to create classes with instruction in the
создавать классы с обучением на
Buryat language, only there are ideas like this,
бурятском языке только идеи есть такие
yes, let’s say,
да М допустим
uh, here’s an article for 2021,
э-э вот статья за 2021 год
so so in total It was written somewhere here
так так в сумме Тут где-то было написано
now
сейчас
I’ll say
скажу
143 that kindergartens where they betray
143 что детских садов где предают
Russian Russian Russian Native language
российски русс российский Родной язык
Nope you don’t understand nya again they don’t teach
нене ты не понял ня ещё раз не преподают
Buryat because where they teach
бурятский потому что там где преподают
Buryat it’s two lessons a week for them
бурятски это два урока в неделю для них
look kids We learn everything in Russian
смотрите детки Мы учимся всё на русском
mathematics in Russian physics in Russian
математика на русском физика на русском
but here you go  two lessons a week, an
а вот вам два урока в неделю язык
aboriginal language like this one that no
аборигенов типа вот такой на котором
one will speak, but you’ll
никто не будет разговаривать но вот вы
learn it. Wow, that’s 143 And so that the
его поучите Вот это да это 143 А чтобы
children can fully  studied in the Buryat
дети полноценно учились на бурятском
language,
языке
no Zero here in the past No, it’s just that
нету Ноль вот в прошлом Нет это просто
this information is not there, just to get it
нет этой информации прям чтобы прям
completely in general. Here, look for
полностью обще возьми Вот возьми вбей
schools with education in Buryat, so I
школы с обучением на бурятском вот я
typed in and they show that only last
вбил и показывают что только в прошлом
year, yes, the idea arose that from September 1,
году да возникла идея что с 1 сентября
uh, to make classes with  training in
ээ сделать классы с обучением на
[music]
[музыка]
Buryat here I see it’s just still new for
бурятском тут я вижу просто ещё новый за
2022, so you see how it’s news that
2022 год вот да видишь как новость что
that’s all that’s planned Or let’s
планирует только и всё Или давайте
go to the city website Ulan ud Yes,
зайдём на городской сайт Улан уд Да
for example,
например
I’ll tell you  explain why this is
я вам это объясни почему это находится
in the state language, yana, that is,
на государственном языке яня то есть
look, you are now confirming Yes, that
смотрите Вы сейчас подтверждаете Да что
national
национальные
pobo zano dekh
побо зано дех
you wouldn’t be taught only in
тебе не бы те учат только на
Russian at the university. You will go only
русском в университет Ты пойдёшь только
in Russian and so on.
на русском и так дальше
Truth Well, because basically all
Правда Ну потому что в основном все
languages ​​because
языки потому что
all  go to
все идут на
Russian,
русском подите
not because you will all study in
не потому что все ты будут изучаться на
Russian. Imagine a person,
русском языке Вот Представьте человек
let’s say, who is in Buryatia,
Допустим который находится в Бурятии о
wants to enter some other
захочет поступить в какой-то другой
university and he just won’t
университет и у него Ну просто у него не
have knowledge of the Russian language
будет Знания русского языка
and how
и как ему
should he be, you just don’t fully understand
быть просто вы не до конца понимаете
the meaning of the
значение
fact that yes, his
вот значение того что да свой язык
native language is his and so a person mainly
родной его и так человек в основном
learns it in the family, but then he learns
изучает в семье но и дальше он постигает
it precisely
его именно
in an educational institution. That is, as a
в учебном заведении То есть как
Technical Specialist. That is, it’s a language you can
Технический специалист То есть это язык
just talk to  mom and that’s it, well,
просто поговорить с мамой и всё да Ну
why is it studied? How is your native
почему как он же изучается Как родной
language fully familiarized with the lessons,
язык вы полно ознакомились с уроками
watch
смотрите
MDT education,
МДТ обуче
mathematics, how to be educated in Russian, I
математ че быть образова на русском я
understood it’s called ethnocide, now the
понял это называется этноцид теперь
second question Are you like a communist? Yes, here you are
второй вопрос Ты как коммунист Да вот ты
you look there the struggle of capitalist
смотришь там борьба капиталистической
Russia of capitalist America Where do you
России капиталистической Америки Как ты
think
считаешь где
Ukraine is a pawn a pawn of imperialism
пра Украина это пешка пешка империализма
No, we’re looking now look everything here
Да нене мы сейчас смотрим смотри всё тут
America and Russia are at war you yourself are the
воюет Америка и Россия вы сами те мне
questions for me It’s very convenient for you I’m asking you
вопросы Вам очень удобно Я вас спрашиваю
look at Where are the rights of
смотрите в Где больше защищены права
workers in America more protected in  The USA or in
рабочих в Америке в США или в
Russia, well, first of all, you need to
России ну это нужно во-первых типа
get acquainted with it exactly like in
ознакомиться именно как в
America. Because I haven’t studied exactly
Америке Потому что я не изучал именно
how they are protected
эци насколько они защищены
in Russia, I, as a person with a higher
в России я как человек с высшим
legal
юридическим
education  wow
образованием вау
yes Super yes, studied the labor codes
да Супер да изучавший трудовые кодексы
very very
весьма очень
well If you judge this way, that is,
хорошо Если так посудите то есть также
we also have overtime, it turns out 40
сверхурочные у нас идёт получается 40
question question can you tell me when
вопрос вопрос можешь мне сказать когда
you remember the last time you had a
ты помнишь последний раз у вас в России
rally or strike of
например митинг или забастовку
trade unions in Russia, a
профсоюзов
rally or a reserve of trade
митинг или запасовка
unions by trade unions Yes, by the way, here
Профсоюзов профсоюзами Да кстати вот
you can  to say not very much in Russia Why is
можно сказать не очень в России А почему
this exactly one of the foundations of socialism,
это же как раз одна из осново социализма
communism, these are strong labor movements
коммунизма это сильные рабочие движения
Yes, trade unions that protect the rights of
Да профсоюзы которые защищают права
workers Why do you have strikes in America
рабочих А что же у вас в Америке есть
Trade Unions Yes, there are rallies of
забастовки Профсоюзов Да митинги
Trade Unions in Europe, but not in Russia.
Профсоюзов в Европе есть а в росссии
Remember directly. Can you
нету Вспомни прямо ина А можешь нагу
figure out when was the last time you had a
лить когда вот когда у вас последний раз
Trade Union meeting? I’m interested, I’m
митинг Профсоюзов был мне интересно же
interested. Maybe they demanded, I don’t
интересно Может там требовали там не
know, some teachers there to raise a
знаю какие-то учителям поднять на
teachers’ union on Red Square,
Красной площади профсоюз учителей
for example.
митинговала например
or those who, for example,
или те кто например
these glassblowers Yes, for example, that there are
э эти стеклодувы Да например что там
prices for bottles to raise, for example,
цены на бутылки чтобы подняли например
they are holding a rally there, maybe there is something like
вот они там митингуют может что-то есть
that, well, let’s say even the EU, well, exactly
такое ну вот допусти даже ес ну именно
not  according to the legislation of the trade union They
не по законодательству профсоюза Они
give them bad rights by the way But that’s
обдают они плохими кстати правами Но вот
it, look, you can google The
именно вот да посмотри можно гуглить
leader of the trade union, courier Kirill of the Ukrainians,
Лидер профсоюза курьер Кирилл украинцев
his last name was yes What was
у него фамилия такая была да Во за что
he imprisoned for, and
его посадили а ну
well, he’s just a left activist like you,
вот вот он как раз левый активист как ты
yes, he’s a communist, a
да вот коммунист
left-wing chairman of the trade union
левый председатель профсоюза
courier they opened a case against him
курьер вот возбудили против него дело
Yes, for posts about protests of couriers,
Да за посты про акции протестов курьеров
that is, he raised the question yes about
то есть вот он поднимал вопрос да о
protests of couriers Yes, through his own
протестах курьеров Да как через свой
word yes And I  understood By Yes, so that Probably
прос да А я понял По Да чтобы Наверно
because they deliver, they
потому что они доставляют они людям
bring bottles to people from different catering establishments
привозят там с разных общепитов бутылки
with different types of water, for example, and
так с разной там водой например да
drink And so they want protection of their rights
питьём И вот они хотят защиты своих прав
Yes, as workers, what happened to him
Да как рабочих что с ним случилось
You can
Можешь
read it to me in general T it
почитать мне в общем Т оно
gave out In general it gave out  union of
выдало В общем выдал профсоюз
couriers, I’ll read it to you like this, and I
курьеров вот я тебе зачитаю так а я
noticed, maybe you can tell
заметил уже может говори
him 22 Yes, repeated violation of the
22 вот ему Да неоднократное нарушение
established procedure for organizing or
установленного порядка организации либо
holding a meeting, a rally, a demonstration, a
проведения собрания митинга демонстрации
procession or picketing,
шествия или пикетирования 5 лет
he was sentenced to 5 years  to one year or months
приговорили его к одно году иче месяцев
in a settlement colony Well, he was released Well, no, he
в колонии поселения Ну освободили Ну нет
was released taking into account the time
так сди освободили с учётом срока
spent in the season. That is,
проведённого в сезо То есть получается
he was kept for
его держали год и 4 месяца Да присудили
a year and 4 months. Yes, he was sentenced to a year and 4 months. Well, I was released because he
год и 4 месяца Ну я освободил потому что
served a sentence. Well, that is, he served
строк прошёл Ну вот то есть он отсидел
a year  and 4 months Well, they could sing more
год и 4 месяца Ну могли бы побольше поть
since this is what you mean, you’re like a communist
раз такое вот то есть ты как коммунист
Yes, they tell you like a trade union
Да тебе говорят вот как профсоюзного
leader Yes, no way for anything Wait, wait, I’m
лидера Да ни за что за Подожди подожди я
just you I’m saying that  So they imprisoned him
просто ты Я говорю что Вот его посадили
for a year and 4 months And you, well, they could have
на год и 4 месяца А ты такой ну могли б
imprisoned him for more And so you see,
и на больше посадить А так видишь с
sir Evie, and I’m a communist, I’m just enjoying
милост Иви а коммунист я кайфую просто
Lenin, then be happy No No, I
Ленин то быть доволен Нет Нет я имею в
mean in terms of the fact that you are very so it
виду в плане того что вы очень так это
draws attention to what  this is the
заостряет внимание что вот такое вот
Russian state Well that's right Well
Россия государство Ну правильно Ну
look very good very bad no
смотри очень хорошее очень плохое не
Wait Look you as a citizen you
Подожди Смотри ты как гражданин ты
support the actions of your
поддерживаешь действия своего
state to repress against
государства по репрессиям против вот
this uh prono
этого э проно
act What's this like  to name that they took him
акте А что как это назвать что его взяли
and imprisoned him, if this is not repression, well, he was
и посадили если это не репрессии ну его
imprisoned for an article about drunkenness, so all
же посадили за статью попи так все
repressions are done under some article,
репрессии по какой-то статье делаются
absolutely everything does not happen that they
абсолютно все не бывает тако что
took a person and did not assign an article to him,
человека взяли и не приписали ему статью
everyone, when the maniac was imprisoned, they also
всем при маньяка посадили тоже
repressed him, no, wait, the maniac killed
репрессировали не ну подожди маньяк убил
tell me who the Russian authorities imprisoned on this case
кого скажи э по делу ли власть России
This is Kirill Ukraintsev Well,
посадила Вот это Кирилла украинцева Ну
I need to figure this out,
мне нужно разобраться в этом де вот
figure it out Look, figure it out for 2
разберись Вот посмотри разберись вот 2
minutes like a lawyer  Figure out what
минуты как юрист Прикинь за что
it’s for. I’m just interested in figuring out the case for a minute. Well, what
е Просто мне интересно минуту
did he do?  look,
написано что и как хоть дейст не смотри
I’m
я вот я
reading, listen, I’ll read it to you while you’re
читаю Слушай я же тебе зачитаю пока ты
looking, look, we’re talking about a
ищешь да смотри вот речь идёт за пост
VKontakte post in which he called on the courier to
ВКонтакт в котором он призывал курьера
go to a mass event on October 30,
выйти на массовое мероприятие 30 октября
2020  on this day, the couriers of the
2020 года вот в этот день курьеры службы
Dely Club delivery service And so on, they
доставки dely Club И так дальше так
staged an action in Moscow protesting against
устроили акцию в Москве протестуя против
fines that significantly reduce their
штрафов которые значительно сокращают их
earnings. Here, the Ukrainians, according to the
заработок вот украинцев по версии
investigation, was the organizer of the action, that
следствия был организатором акции то
is, He was imprisoned for a meeting of Trade Unions
есть Его посадили за митинг Профсоюзов
for this is what communists should do.
за вот то что должны делать коммунисты
That is,
То есть
you  I’m telling you again as a lawyer. I
ты я ещё раз вам говорю как юрист Я же
can’t get acquainted with the case material
не могу ознакомиться с материалом дела
because it’s not in the public domain. Well,
потому что оно нет в открытом доступе Ну
either the browser just doesn’t give it to me.
либо Мне просто не выдаёт браузер могу
Well, no,
Ну так нет так
look, this is this, this is the material  The media
смотри это это это материал Сми сми
can you put him in prison again, again, again,
можешь ещё раз ещё раз ещё раз его
under what article did you read,
посадили По какой статье Ты же прочитал
but if not violation of rallies, meetings,
да как не нарушение митингов собраний
everything else? What do you think? Is
всего остального Как ты считаешь
this a democratic norm? Yes Yes, for the
Демократическая ли это норма да Да за
so-called unauthorized
так называемый несанкционированный
rally Yes Peaceful, he didn’t kill anyone,
митинг Да Мирный он никого не убил
nothing Yes, he was imprisoned then  there is
ничего Да его посадили то есть
criminalization
криминализация
of rallies. Well, I say again, violation of the
митингов Ну я ещё раз говорю нарушение
rules of the assembly, look correctly,
правил собрания правильно смотри
for example, if they say, for example, that whoever
например если э говорят например что кто
opens the race will be imprisoned, for example, for 10
откроет род того посадят например на 10
years. Yes, there will be such an article here,
лет Да вот будет такая статья вот тут
violation of the rules of the assembly. That’s how you are  As a
нарушение правил собрания Вот как ты Как
lawyer Yes, as a lawyer and as a communist, yes,
юрист Да как юрист и как коммунист да
tell me. Did they
скажи
do the right thing in what they introduced? In
Правильно ли сделали что внесли Это вас
my opinion, in the twentieth year, yes, they introduced this
по-моему в двадцатом году да внесли эту
norm.
норму
And for criminal liability for
А за криминальная ответственность за
violating the rules of organizing
нарушение там правил организации
rallies there, this is a very stupid analogy, and the fact
митингов это очень глупо аналогия причём
that someone if carried out Look  I
то что кто-то если ведётся Смотри я
just asked your opinion, you as a lawyer
просто спросил твоё мнение ты как юрист
and a communist, tell me, do you support what
и коммунист скажи ты поддерживаешь то
you have in your legislation, they introduced
что у вас ваше законодательство внесли
this
вот эту
article on
статью по
violation of the rules for organizing
нарушении правил организации
rallies, this is the same thing, if let’s say I,
митингов это тоже самое если допустим я
as a Motorist  you support from
как Автомобилист вы поддерживаете от
the fact that let’s say they put it into the traffic rules in the
того что допустим вели в правило ПДД в
Koa PRF the rule there is allowable to run
коа прф правило там допустим переехать
through a red light
на красный свет
sra No look again, look if you
сра Нет ещё раз смотри смотри если ты
ask me, as a lawyer, tell me do you
меня спросишь ты как юрист скажи
support administrative
поддерживаешь ли ты административную
liability for driving through a red
ответственность за приезд на красный
light, I’ll say Yes, I support that  Now,
свет я скажу Да я поддерживаю так вот
if you ask me under the
если ты меня спросишь поде
article for execution for driving without a belt, I
статью за расстрел за езду без ремня я
will say I don’t
скажу я не
support it, then I’m asking you,
поддерживаю то вот я тебя спрашиваю
look, you see that this is not
смотри Ты видишь что это не
administrative responsibility, but
административная ответственность а
criminal sweaty because because the person
уголовная потная потому потому что чело
repeatedly support do you yes
неоднократно поддерживаешь ли ты да
criminal liability for
уголовную ответственность за
repeated violations of holding
неоднократное нарушение проведения
rallies well, first of all it is necessary to
митингов ну во-первых нужно
change,
именно Измени
depending on what kind of violation the violation is a
смотря какое нарушение нарушение - это
very huge concept, let’s say a person
очень огромное понятие допустим человек
calls, let’s say a person peacefully without
призовёт вот допустим человек мирно без
anything and he will be imprisoned for the violation there is a
ничего и его посадят за нарушение есть
person  Let's say He says there
человек Допустим Он скажет там
to throw stones with sticks and build
закидывать э палками камнями строить
barricades - this is also a
Баррикады - это тоже
violation of holding rallies and they are carried out
нарушение проведения митингов и их пасат
for the same thing, these are two Although these are
по одной и той же стать это две Хотя это
two two two different actions, roughly speaking
два две два разных действия грубо говоря
again  that means, look at the
ещё раз значит смотри
obs. That is, if a person
обс Вот то есть если человек два раза
held an unauthorized rally twice. That is,
прол несанкционированный митинг То есть
he submitted, for example,
он подал например
that the rally should be allowed. Yes, he was not allowed,
что разрешить митинг Да ему не разрешили
but he gathered, yes, in the amount of 10
а он собрался да вот в количестве 10
people. The first time he receives
человек Он первый раз у вас получает
an administrative charge from you, the second time he receives a
административку второй раз он получает
crime, so I’m you  I ask, do you
криминал так вот Я тебя спрашиваю ты
support what kind of repeated, that
поддерживаешь то что за неоднократный то
is, repeated holding of a rally,
есть повторное проведение него митинга
people should be put in prison
людей надо садить в тюрьму
in
именно в
prison, I’m telling you this again, I’m just
тюрьму я вам ещё раз это говорю я просто
not, I’m tired of repeating one thing at a time Well,
нет я я устал повторять по одно Ну
look  So I’m saying, Look, I think
смотри вот я говорю Смотри я считаю да
that putting people in prison, that is,
что садить людей в тюрму то есть
criminalizing
криминалити несанкционированное
holding an unauthorized rally is not possible. This is wrong,
проведение митинг нельзя Это неправильно
but for example, about an administrative
да вот например про административный
fine. Yes, you can talk about it,
штраф Да можно у вас там говорить было
although here, for example, look, we
бы хотя у нас например смотри вот у нас
don’t have authorized rallies, we
нету санкционированных митингов мы не
shouldn’t receive  The decision to attend a rally is
должны получать шение На митинг мы
simply in Ukraine.
просто вот в Украине
Yes, you
Да ты
notify that you will hold
уведомляет о том что будешь проводить
a rally if, for example, the Khmelnitsky
митинг если например Хмельницкий
city council wants to consider that
городской совет хочет считать что нельзя
this rally cannot be held for some
проводить этот митинг по каким-то
reason. Yes, then it goes to
причинам Да он тогда делает обращение в
court and only  the court considering it can
суд и только суд рассматривая может
ban this rally or ban it at
запретить этот митинг или запретить в
certain hours
определённые часы потому
because only the court Yes, only the court,
что только суд Да только суд вот у вас
but you need to get permission from an official,
же нужно получить разрешение у чиновника
even if that’s not the case, look again if I
даже не так сри ещё раз смотри если я у
hold a rally at my place Yes, without notifying the
себя проведу митинг Да без уведомление
local authorities Yes, they won’t put me in prison
местных властей Да меня не посадят в
prison You have a person who has been imprisoned and
тюрьму У вас же человека посадят и
imprisoned and not a single one, I’m just
посадили и ни одного я тебя просто
asking you. Look, I think that a criminologist should not
спрашиваю Смотри я считаю что нельзя
hold rallies, you
криминалиста проведение митингов ты
think as a lawyer and as a
считаешь как вот как юрист и как
communist. Is it possible to put people in prison
коммунист Можно ли людей сажать в тюрьму
for repeated authorized
за неоднократное санкционированное
holding of
проведение
rallies, I can repeat again
митингов ещё раз могу повторить
Repeat there are certain
Повтори есть определённые
interpretations What exactly could be a
трактовки Что именно может быть
violation Most likely in the interpretation of this
нарушение Скорее всего в трактова данной
article under which Yes,
статьи под которую Да подпадают различны
various moments fall under the
различные моменты по
subject on the subjective side, namely
субъектом по субъективной стороне именно
moments in
моменты
terms of yes, I can give you one more
плане да я вам ещ раз могу привести
example of one person Let’s say  he just
пример один человек Допустим он просто
got ready at the wrong time and didn’t get
собрался не в нужное время не получил
permission. And there is another similar moment
разрешение А есть другой такой же момент
in which a person, let’s say, orders
при котором человек допустим прикажет
there, I don’t
там не
know, smash cars, everything else,
знаю Мить автомобили всё остальное
throw stones at the police, everything
кидать камнями в сотрудников полиции всё
else, the article is the same again
остальное статья одна и та же ещё раз
look, let me read you
смотри Давай я зачитаю тебе
212t responsible for repeatedly violating the
212т ответст за неоднократно нарушение
established order or holding a
установленого порядка либо проведения
meeting, a rally, a demonstration, a pole or
собрания митинга демонстрации шест или
picketing in the form of a fine in the amount you need to
пикетирование в виде штрафа размере надо
go, but you need to go to the Code of Administrative Offenses, this is not
зайти а в КоАП надо зайти это не в КоАП
a crime, I’m not talking about the cop, it’s
Это уголовка не я говорю в копе
written up for violation of SOBR, and the Kuap
расписано нарушение СОБРа причём куап
Code of Administrative Offenses is  you have administrative ones, and
КоАП - это административные у вас А это
we are criminal ones, looking at repeated
мы уголовные смотрим неоднократное
violations, repeated violations
нарушение неоднократное нарушение ещё
again, look again, here we are now, we are
раз ещё раз смотри вот мы сейчас мы
now reading the article on which we were convicted  of
сейчас читаем статью по которой осудили
this dude, this is an article of the Criminal
этого чувака это статья Уголовного
Code. What does it have to do with the administrative one?
кодекса Причём тут административный
If anything, our Criminal
вот у нас если что у нас Уголовный
Code is not very different from yours.
кодекс он не сильно отличается от вашего
There is an article of the Russian Federation, which says
есть статья прф в которой написано
violation of the rules of the assembly, and what does the
нарушение правил собрания причём причём
PV have to do with it, look, we are now talking about
ПВ смотри мы мы сейчас говорим про
Criminal liability. Here is the article
Криминальную ответственность Вот статья
for which this  Kirill
вот за которую этого Кирилла
was imprisoned, it clearly states that
посадили вот в ней чётко говорится Да
violation of the established procedure for
нарушение установлено порядка
organizing or holding a
организации или проведения собрания
meeting, demonstration, procession or
митинга демонстрации шествия или
picketing is recognized as committed
пикетирования признаётся совершенным
repeatedly if the
неоднократно в том случае если ранее
person was previously involved in  administrative
лицо привлекалось к административной
responsibility for committing
ответственности за совершение
administrative offenses,
административных правонарушений
but this one held an unauthorized rally in six months,
но этой за полгода провед ра
it will be
несанкционированный митинг это будет
administrative, but if you are
административка но если третий раз тебя
brought to criminal responsibility for the third time,
привлекают к уголовной ответственности
I’m right there about throwing
вот я тебя спра там нету про кидания
stones about setting cars on fire. It’s just that you
камнями про поджоги машин Просто ты три
went out without permission three times with a
раза вышел не санкционированно с
poster in six months, you will support  Yes,
плакатом за полгода поддержишь
deprive people of their
людей Да лишать
freedom and
свободы и привлекать к уголовной
prosecute them for holding unauthorized rallies three times in six months,
ответственности за три раза за полгода
you, as a
несанкционированные митинги ты как
communist and as a
коммунист и как
lawyer, I read the article  Yeah, well,
юрист я читаю статью Ага ну и
here it is again Well, read it Come on, come on
вот ещё раз Ну прочитай Давай давай Нет
No, I won’t read it again, I’ll just repeat what’s there
не буду читать ещ просто повторю что
once
есть раз
Yes, you need to
Да нужно
first interpret precisely
во-первых трактовать именно вот именно
Article
статью
22.2, it should be for a more serious
22.2 она долж быть за более серьёзное
violation of the rules of meetings.
нарушение правил собрания митингов
Yes, 22.2 is what 21.2 is all about.
Да 22.2 это вообще о чём за
you yourself read it, I’m
21.2 Ну вы же сами читали я
point one for some reason, just in
а точка один почему-то просто в
some articles for some reason it seems
некоторых статья почему-то на кажется
22.2 I’m also sitting here thinking for some reason
22.2 я тоже сижу думаю почему-то статьи
there’s no article Well look  I read it to myself, there
нету вот Ну смотри вот я себе её
are no disagreements,
прочитал там нету никаких разногласий
everything is clear there. That is, if you
там всё чётко То есть если ты на
held an
получается более двух раз проводил
unauthorized rally more than twice for 180 days, that is, six months, that’s criminal.
несанкционированный митинг Всё теперь у
Now I’m asking you clearly, there are
Вот я тебя спрашиваю чётко тут нету
no disagreements, this is criminal  The
никаких разногласий это же криминальный
Criminal Code describes everything very clearly
Уголовный кодекс там всё очень чётко
Yes, if like you, as a lawyer and a
описано Да Если как ты Как юрист и
communist, you think that if a person in Russia
коммунист считаешь если человек в России
held an unauthorized rally three times in six months,
три раза за полгода провёл
should he be
несанкционированный митинг Нужно ли его
prosecuted?  responsibility
привлекать к уголовной ответственности
Just tell me, as a lawyer and as a
Просто мне скажи как юрист и как
communist, do you support this or don’t
коммунист поддерживаешь ты это или не
you
поддерживаешь
support the parties as a lawyer? Because
поддерживаю стороны как юрист Потому что
if a citizen on the one hand does not
если гражданин с одной стороны не
understand, he has violated since he
понимает он наруш раз
violated, look, I mean, support you
наруш смотри я имею в виду Поддержи ты
as a Lawyer that such a norm is needed in the
как Юрист что нужна такая норма в
Constitution Oh, no  Constitution And in the
Конституции Ой не в Конституции А в
criminal code as a lawyer Yes, as a
уголовном кодексе как юрист Да как
communist no wait, why as a lawyer do
коммунист нет подожди а почему как юрист
you think that such a norm should be included
ты считаешь что такую норму надо внести
in the Criminal Code? Because as a lawyer
в Уголовный кодекс потому что как юрист
I feel with ro I think this is on the part of the
я чувствую со ро я это считаю со стороны
state  when a person violated the law
государства когда человек э раз нарушил
once, violated the law twice, then
раз нарушил закон два два нарушил то и
he violated the law for the third time already. Okay, driving through
он в третий раз уже его смо Окей проезд
without this or
в без этого или вот
passing, running a red light is an
проход переход на красный свет это
administrative
административное
offense Yes, but it does not go to the
правонарушение Да но оно не переходит в
Criminal Code if you do it three times in
Уголовный ко ес если ты три раза за
six months  Yes, if you run a red light,
полгода Да перейдёшь на красный свет
you won’t be sent to prison, there is such
тебя же не садят в тюрьму есть такое
a thing as a principle, like proportionality,
понятие как принцип как соразмерность
such a
такой
principle Well done Well done, look it
принцип Молодец Молодец то смотри
turns out If a person
получается Если человек три раза
runs a red light three times in six months
переходит за полгода на красный свет его
because he repeats
из-за того что он повторяет
administrative offense Yes, they don’t
административное правонарушение Да не
go to prison, but what if a person
садят в тюрьму а а если человек три раза
held an unauthorized rally three times in six months,
за полгода провёл несанкционированный
for some reason you support that there should
митинг почему-то ты поддерживаешь чтобы
be such a rule that people should be put in
такая норма была чтоб садили людей в
prison, just like a lawyer. You are, and I have a question for you.
тюрьму точно юрист Вы да А у меня к тебе
You’re definitely a lawyer, I
вопрос Ты точно юрист у меня корочка
have my credentials to show you.  Why do I need your crusts? I’m
есть показать Зачем мне твой корочки Я
asking like that, not I’m just listening to you.
спрашиваю так не Мне просто вас слушаю
You’re somehow very strange, well, look
Вы как-то очень странно те ну смотри ещё
again, I’m th Where did this norm come from? You can simply
раз я го Откуда взялась Эта норма просто
hear it even in the language.  Where did
слышно даже по языку че че боле откуда
this norm come from in the Criminal
Откуда взялась Эта норма в Уголовном
Code, yes, that is, you have a legislative
кодексе да то есть у вас законодательный
body there, the State Duma, yes, or whatever you
орган там Госдума да Или как она у вас
call it, yes, the State Duma, it introduced this norm
да Госдума называе она внесла эту норму
into the criminal legislation,
в уголовное законодательство
and so on. Or it might not have introduced exactly this, for
так так вот А могла не внести именно это
example, for switching to red
так например за переход на красный свет
multiple light Yes, they don’t go to prison And for
многократный Да не садят в тюрьму А за
That is, you think. You personally
То есть ты считаешь Вот ты лично
think that yes, the State Duma did the
считаешь что да Госдума сделала
right thing by introducing this article so that
правильно что внесла эту статью чтобы
people for three times of unauthorized
людей за три раза несанкционированных
rallies for  for six months they were sent to
митингов за полгода с садили в
prison in proportion to that. That is, you think
Тюрягу соразмерно То есть ты считаешь
that this is correct. Yes, yes, that it is
что это правильно Да да что это
proportionate. You’re a communist, which is
соразмерно вот это ты коммунист что
socially dangerous. I’m talking now, like
общественно опасно де я сечас говорю как
in the World Cup, in the World Cup, it’s socially dangerous.
вот вот в ЧМ в ЧМ общественно опас Вот
You’re right, it’s socially dangerous,
ты правильно ска общественно опас
you squeezed it out, yes. What?  socially
выдавил ты это да В чём общественно
dangerous
опасное
act
деяние
rally Well, because it can
митинг Ну потому что он может
paralyze traffic, let’s say
парализовать движение допустим вот
let’s say it will pass, I don’t know the nits there along the
допустим пройдёт он не знаю гнид там по
main street of the city, look No,
центральной улице города смотри Нет е
no
нет
look, if he paralyzed it, there are
смотри если он парализовал это есть
naslidki, as it is in Russian, consequences.
наслидки как это по-русски следствия Да
Yes, there is a legacy like in Russian, well, if
вот есть наслед типа по-русски ну если
he paralyzed the movement, there are these
он парализовал движение есть вот эти
consequences, there are paralyzed movements,
следствиями есть парализованные движение
some losses. Yes, he can be paid for this.
какие-то убытки Да его можно за это А
But if a person holds a rally
вот если человек да проводит митинг
near  city ​​hall or on Red Square, here are
возле мэрии или на Красной площади вот
10 people, no naslidkom I
10 человек никаких наслидком Как это
don’t know how it is in Russian, it doesn’t come, it doesn’t
по-русски не знаю не настаёт не
come Yes, there are consequences, most likely
наступает Да последствий скорее всего
consequences Yes, there are consequences Yes, there are no
последствия Да последствия Да никаких
consequences, but what is the
последствий не настаёт да то в чём
public  Well, let’s say
общественная вот э скажем
it in Russian, well, a single picket
как это по-русски ну одиночный пикет не
is not a single picket, here are 10 people 10
является не Одиночный вот 10 человек 10
people they came out Yes, this is all an
человек они вышли Да всё это уже митинг
unauthorized rally Toto What is the danger
несанкционированный Тото В чём опасность
for society of an unauthorized
для общества несанкционированного
rally So you need to imprison a
митинга Так что нужно садить
person Well, this is already the problem of the
человека Ну это уже это уже проблема
adopted law itself  its
самого принятого закона его
wording is the law that was adopted, but you will
формулировки вот принятого закона но ты
support that this law was adopted, that
поддержишь что этот закон приняли что
this norm
эту норму
was adopted, I say the law was adopted, but the law has
приняли говорю закон приняли но в прави
incorrect wording, that’s
неправильное формулировки есть вот и
all.
всё Покажи свою корочку
Show your credentials as a lawyer. I want to see at which
юрист Я хочу посмотреть в каком
university they give
университете таких штампуют
me such people.  I’m just wondering where yours are
мне просто интересно где ваши таки
stamping the
штампуют
Malinets University of Management and the
малинецкий университет управления та
rights I have is approximately proportional to yours,
права У меня примерно соразмерно вашему
come
давай
on now, I’ll do the red stuff so that it is T
сечас я красники сделаю чтобы это было Т
pros I just really need to not
прос Мне просто нужно очень не
turn it off like this, so that
сворачивал вот так чтоб
the trick will be that you
просто фокус будет что ты
show
показывать вот
this in the direction of preparation 4301 law
это по направлению подготовки 4301 юри
prosh state  decision of the
прош государственного решение
state commission awarded the
государственно комиссии присвоена
qualification bola about the name of the
квалификация бола про название
university Pacific
университета Тихоокеанский
State University what
Государственный университет какой
Pacific State
Тихоокеанский Государственный
University Pacific is somewhere in the
университет Тихоокеанский это где-то на
Far East yes All I am  now I understand, yes,
Дальнем Востоке да Всё Я теперь понял да
that the Pacific State
Что Тихоокеанский Государственный
University is churning out awesome
университет штампует офигенных юристов
communist lawyers on this law, I see it too,
коммунистов на этом закони я смотрю тоже
but not SPO Slava Ukraine come on
да не СПО Слава Украине давай
Oh damn, these are all home-grown communists
Ой блин эти все доморощенные коммунисты
Yes, why the hell do you
Да
call yourself a communist
ээ нахрена ты называешь себя коммунистом
If you don’t even understand it, I [ __ ]
Если ты даже не разбираешься я блин
understand your communism more than
больше разбираюсь в твоём коммунизме чем
you  but it’s burning in the right It’s just tough, yes, that
ты а горит праве Это просто жесть да то
is, the dude is in all seriousness Yes, he
есть чувак на полном серьёзе Да
supports that, well, there’s such an
поддерживает что э ну вот есть такая
article, which means it’s normal. So what?  they imprison you, like, well, there
статья значит норм Да что садят типа ну
is an article, he means he violated, yes, that
статья же есть он значит нарушил да то
is, if they make you an article, yes What, for
есть если вам сделают статью да Что
example, for three ears of corn, yes, or there What, who are
например за три колоска да или там Что
you, for example, works less than 8
что ты кто например работает меньше 8
hours a day, and he goes to prison and they
часов в сутки да того в тюрьму и тебя
put you in prison and say, well, look
садят в тюрьму и говорят ну так смотри
there is an article. This is not a violation.
есть же статья Это же не нарушение Да
Yes, you were imprisoned under the article. The question is:
вот тебя по статье посадили вопрос в том
Is such an article necessary in the legislation?
Нужна ли такая статья в законодательстве
Yes, that’s the point; yes, a totalitarian
Да в том-то и есть да что тоталитарное
state restricts you, a
государство оно ограничивает тебя
communist,
коммунист
in the right to freely assemble and the right to
в праве свободно собираться в праве
hold demonstrations.  marches,
проводить митинги демонстрации шествия
yes, that is, and here you have the trade unions of a
да то есть И вот у вас профсоюзы
man who were imprisoned simply because
человека посадили просто да потому что
he was a union of couriers and demanded
он профсоюзом курьеров был да и требовал
that employers not illegally remove fines from them.
что с них работодатели штрафы не
Yes, so that they would introduce a
неправомерно снимают Да чтобы ввели
settlement of this issue, they imprisoned all the dude
урегулировать этот вопрос всё чувака
because in America, yes, in this
посадили потому что в Америке да в этой
capitalist, imperialist
капиталистической империалистический
trade unions there are  yes, no matter how it is in
профсоюзы есть да как бы там ни было в
Europe, there are trade unions in general. If we look at
Европе вообще профсоюзы Если мы смотрим
some France Yes Germany,
там какую-то Францию Да Германию там
trade unions are generally very strong there, yes And
профсоюзы вообще очень сильно стоят да А
you have trade unions  subscribe to my
у вас профсоюзы сидят подпишись на мий
Instagram I don’t know why this is for
Instagram Я не знаю для чого це тоб для
why there is to marvel at the ocey face Ale
чого тоб там дивитись на оцей фейс Але
for you this is two or three clicks and you are
для тебе це оди два або три клика а ты
three to me and I will be KTA in me there are
тримае мене и я буду КТА в мене там
fouls and in me there will be a classy mood to be
фолов и в мене буде класний настрий щоб
robiti but cool  video message on th Instagram
робити но крут вдео пись на й Instagram
Popik Andriy like
Попик Андрий вот
this, let me
так давай я тебя
check for you L
чекаю L